{"data":[{"question":"The whole club greeted me as though I ___ a member of the club.","a":"were","b":"am","c":"should be","d":"would","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Clauses that start with as if\/as though express unreality, improbability or doubt if they are followed by an unreal tense \n- The simple past tense is used if we talk about an unreal situation in the present ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"___, the situation would have been all right.","a":"The chief had been here","b":"Here the chief had been","c":"Been here the chief had","d":"Had the chief been here","answer":"4","explain":"\n- Sometimes conditional forms are inverted as a means of sounding more formal. In this case, the conditional 'if' is dropped and the inverted forms takes the place of the 'if clause' \n- Inversion clause: auxiliary + subject + main verb","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"If the alarm hadn't woken us, we _________ the fire and it ___ the houses upstairs and next door.","a":"wouldn't have noticed, might have spread to","b":"hadn't noticed, had spread to","c":"didn't notice, spread to","d":"wouldn't notice, would have spread to","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Conditional Sentence Type 3:  used to talk about things that didn't happened in the past and the consequence if they had happened\n+ Form: if + Past Perfect, would + have + Past Participle\n- Might have PP: used as the past tense of 'may' when reporting that someone talked or thought about the possibility of something","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"I wish I _________ to talk this over with Mr. Wang when he was here this morning","a":"should be able","b":"had been able","c":"were able","d":"have been able","answer":"2","explain":"\n- A wish about the past: Wish clause,had PP\/ should, could have PP ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"If Kenny were to do it, the outcome ___ totally different.","a":"would be","b":"will be","c":"would have been","d":"should be","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Conditional Sentence Type 2: used to talk about unlikely, imaginary or untrue events or situations \n- Form: if + Simple Past, would + Infinitive ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"___ this noon, he would get there by tomorrow's evening .","a":"Was your president leaving","b":"If your president leaves","c":"Were your president to leave","d":"Would your president leave","answer":"3","explain":"- We use the inversion form with conditional structure type II (the verb and the subject are inverted)","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"It was a sunny day yesterday. I wish I ___ at the seaside then.","a":"had been","b":"were","c":"should have been","d":"should be","answer":"1","explain":"\n- A wish about the past: Wish clause,had PP\/ should, could have PP ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"The big fire in the morning ___ the whole apartment, but the heavy rain helped it.","a":"could have burned down","b":"might be burning down","c":"must have been burned downs","d":"should have been burned down","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Could have PP: used to say that something was a possibility in the past, but did not actually happen","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"If only I _________ as wise as you are!","a":"am","b":"be","c":"being","d":"were","answer":"4","explain":"\n- If only = wish ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"Should it rain, the people ___.","a":"would be saved","b":"will be saved","c":"would have been saved","d":"had been saved","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Sometimes conditional forms are inverted as a means of sounding more formal. In this case, the conditional 'if' is dropped and the inverted forms takes the place of the 'if clause' \n- Inversion clause: auxiliary + subject + main verb","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"}]}